Bruno Alfirević

Vinodolska 42, 21000 Split, Croatia Email: bruno.alfirevic@gmail.com
Phone: +385 91 5223711

Linked in profile: http://www.linkedin.com/in/brunoalfirevic
Github profile: https://github.com/brunoalfirevic

Software engineering professional with 18 years of experience in professional software development. Majority of experience is in product development targeted at end users (businesses as well as consumers) in international market, taking part in all aspects of product development (gathering requirements, feature design and product steering, technical design and architecture, choice of technologies, database design, programming, testing and documentation).

My software development philosophy consists of striving for technical excellence as a way towards fastest delivery of required functionality for the user. Constant learning of new technologies, iterative approach to development in light of changing circumstances, clear communication and shared knowledge among the team are all important factors in this pursuit.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONTRACTING)

HR Cloud December 2019 - Present

Continuation of previous work (done while working full time for HR Cloud) on insurance brokerage web application (C#/Typescript).

GammaChef August 2019 – Present

Design and development (C# backend and database design) of ordering and scheduling application for robotic kitchen restaurant.

HR Cloud March 2019 – April 2019

Finishing development and handover of duties for applications previously developed for HR Cloud.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (FULL-TIME EMPLOYMENT)

HR Cloud

Software Architect and Team Lead March 2013 – February 2019

C# developer — Online job search engine and job application platform for public sector jobs in US

- Development of new version of web application for searching and applying to jobs in United States public sector
- Design and development of integration with existing system for resume processing

C# developer - Web application for performance evaluation of employees (SaaS)

- Maintenance and development of web application for performance evaluation of employees, mostly focusing on public sector companies
- Helping with design of database migration and deployment system, used for tracking db changes

during the development as well as deployment to production

Lead developer and architect (C#) – Human resources management web application (SaaS)

- Development of new web application for human resources management, focusing on private sector
- Gathering requirements from people in customer support and other domain experts
- Coordinating the development with multiple teams spread across multiple continents and time zones

Architect and team lead (C#/Typescript) – Insurance brokerage web application (SaaS)

- Development of new web application in insurance brokerage industry for a client
- Mentoring, coordinating and leading a team of developers, testers and a business analyst
- Responsible for delivering features on time and in accordance with client requirements
- Laying down the architectural groundwork and implementing application features

Hattrick Sports Group

Senior Software Developer July 2011 – February 2013

C# developer – Betting applications and backend services

- Maintenance and development of applications that enable Hattrick's betting business
- Introduced and mentored other developers in better version control practices

Lead developer (C#) – Online betting website

- Development of Hattrick's online betting website from it's inception
- Collecting and analyzing requirements for betting website itself, as well as required integration points with the rest of betting infrastructure
- Mentoring other developers in web development techniques

Pravi klik

Software Architect March 2008 – June 2011

Lead developer – GoHome real estate search engine and analytics engine for real estate agencies

- Software development and feature design of company's core product
- Worked on optimizing and scaling of real estate search engine
- Introduced source control system and unit testing to company's software engineering process
- Conceived and implemented configuration management system for easy deployment and rollback of multiple software components for multiple search engine instances (one search engine + supporting services for each country where GoHome was present)

Lead developer – Lead generation platform for real estate agencies

• Development of new lead generation platform for real estate agencies, based on individual user real estate search data

Polar

Chief Software Developer 2001 – March 2008

Lead developer (C#) – Polar Help Desk (SaaS version)

- Served as a main technical architect of application
- Participated in feature design and steering a product
- Implemented large part of application
- Introduced many modern technologies and engineering techniques such as unit testing, object relational mapping, as well as clean and structured approach to client side interface development (clean HTML, usage of ¡Query)
- · Ported application to work with PostgreSQL database in addition to original MS SQL Server
- Introduced continuous integration practices
- Steered development methodology towards iterative approach
- Mentored new programmers on the project

C# developer – Polar Help Desk

- Participated in product requirement analysis and feature design
- Participated in architecting and implementation of software product

Lead developer (C++, C#, Delphi) - Spell Checker COM and .NET components

- Design of major part of product functionality and features
- · Implemented majority of the product itself

EDUCATION AND LANGUAGES

- Master's degree in Computer Science
- Proficiency in English

EXPERIENCE WITH TECHNOLOGIES AND SKILLS

- In-depth knowledge of C# programming language (including C# 7.0 additions), .NET Framework and .NET Core
- Extensive experience with metaprogramming on .NET platform (runtime codegeneration, LINQ expression trees generation and manipulation)
- Active knowledge of web development technologies, including HTTP, Javascript, Typescript, HTML and some CSS.
- Data storage technologies: relational database design principles, SQL (MS SQL Server and PostgreSQL), Lucene.NET, MongoDB, SOLR
- Experience designing and implementing RESTful web services
- Experience designing and implementing both server-side rendered web applications and single-page web applications
- Professional experience with C++ language and Delphi programming environment
- Hobbyist experience with Java, Ruby and Clojure programming languages
- Knowledge of functional programming principles, design patterns, object-oriented design and domain driven design
- Frameworks/libraries: dependency injection (Spring.NET, StructureMap, Autofac, DryIoC), object-relational mapping (NHibernate, Entity Framework), web development (ASP.NET/MVC, jQuery, AngularJS, Vue.js), unit testing (NUnit, BDD)
- Ability to function in a team as well as a technical lead for a team